[Music]
hello and welcome to the junkyard love
podcast
at what age do we learn how to have
better conversations
at what age do we learn to have better
conversations with ourselves
[Music]
no
knowledge is power
[Music]
cool so um i wanted to start it out
welcome to the junkyard love podcast i'm
really i'm really pumped to talk to both
of you today
um i wanted to kind of read just a
little
uh glimpse of your bio here that was
sent over to me
um and then maybe you two can elaborate
on it and introduce yourselves and
tell everybody what you do so well so um
irwan and alicia devon use their
backgrounds in zen buddhism psychology
and women's sexuality studies to develop
the pleasure course
which has helped thousands achieve their
ideal love lives they provide a safe
a safe place to explore psychological
inquiry
pleasure and sexuality recently their
work has focused on pandemic related
intimacy issues with singles dating
intimacy during the pandemic
and couples physically close but losing
connection i think it's
wonderful what you guys do i think it's
a great time for that sort of thing
right now so
welcome to the podcast hello hi
great to be here
so what i love god i love that we do
that
i appreciate you reading it like i love
the reflection is nice thank you yeah
yeah yeah of course so um give me
give me kind of a how did you get into
this i mean
erwin i think it was a 1995 you started
doing this
and then we should join later background
first okay 1995
i had a very far out love life i had a
very far out girlfriend i had a very far
out love life was going to the
university of california santa cruz
uh you know which is a place that's just
kind of open for possibility
especially in 1995 and
that was i was studying psychology and
that was after needing
a an enormous amount of psychological
help as a teenager
i was in psychoanalysis multiple days a
week
i had an obsessive compulsive disorder
my family had basically been destroyed
my mother
left when i was seven my father was a
street
fighter my mother died when i was 15.
i'd barely seen her since i was seven
like and it just goes on
and on and on and on that's that's the
good part okay
so i did a ton of psychological work
started in new york came out to
california
and took every possible workshop i could
you know anything and everything i'm
running around the room waving my arms
i'm
doing primal therapy i'm studying
psychology i'm in
you know all the rest of this kind of
stuff and in the middle of all that i
realized
what i was the most passionate about the
most interested in especially after i
kind of sorted myself out
psychologically
was women i was really interested
in women i was really now this is it
saying that now feels like well so is
everybody
but for me it was like a big you know
like aha
wow okay i know what i'm interested in
right after i sort of sorted myself out
having taught all those workshops i was
teaching for one of the world's largest
organizations
then i just branched out started
teaching about romance and relationship
it was more about kind of sex and a wild
lifestyle
early on because that's what i was
living long story short
later on alicia came into the picture uh
uh what are you what trained me or
husbanded me or
what do you say turn me into a husband
or how do you know what's this word for
that yes
i don't like the word tame because you
are my wild man
yeah yeah but something domesticated
domestication you know so so one of the
biggest things we support people in now
is you know if they're single getting
into relationships or if they're in a
couple
how do you have a domestic situation
much less in a pandemic that's still
rocking it's still hot that's still
turned on yeah
so that's how i that's how i got into it
how about you yes yes well i was
i had like the opposite upbringing as
arowan i grew up in l.a
had a really stable family a little
brother two parents
they're all great and my parents still
live in the same house that i grew up in
it was nice it was kind of a bubble you
know it was sheltered and of course
i had issues like everybody had issues
but as i went through
college i started to feel like
is this all there is that question like
i'm pretty comfortable
things are okay and there was this
sneaking in of like
depression and emptiness and what is
this and that
drove me into therapy and
like everyone was describing these
workshops i'd go to these incredible
like women's
workshops and we were in sweat lodges
and drumming and all this kind of stuff
and i had these really powerful
awakenings like oh my gosh there is way
more to life than i thought so it starts
me on the path of psychology
i went to grad school got a master's in
psychology
and then i remember the moment
where i realized i was totally obsessed
with not just psychology
but sexuality female sexuality and how
that
jives with our psychology and i was like
holed up in the library reading these
old texts at my grad school trying to
like get information
really about myself right and my body
and opening and everything
and i couldn't quite like scratch the
itch that way
reading books even though books are
great
and one day my friend shayna
in my program was like alicia i just met
this guy erwin you have to meet him you
know he teaches these
classes in san francisco all about
pleasure
and orgasm and being present in
relationship i'm like
i gotta get to this guy like right away
so she brings me over to air ones and he
was leading this group there were like
20 people in the room
sitting around in a circle doing these
communication games
and i remember walking like literally
crossing the threshold of his front door
and feeling like i just came on to
ecstasy or something i'm like this is
amazing and people were like
looking into each other's eyes as they
were talking and talking about real
stuff
you know so i got interested i was very
interested in erwin
i i was in another relationship at the
time that was like
going downhill and this made it go
downhill
way faster we broke up and then you know
we have a long funny story of how we got
back into touch but we came back
together
we started dating and like erwin was
just rocking my world in all ways
and so i never left wow
wow wonderful and now you guys do this
together and you've expanded your
teachings and you've you've progressed
over time
and and i'm sure just gotten better and
and uh
you know made your program more specific
it's so so what what have you found
i mean i i really like sticking in where
where you guys have been working on
helping people during the pandemic
because i feel like that probably
totally threw a curveball
to what you guys typically do i mean
because you did live events before and
so that's suddenly
not able to do that so how did it change
when the pandemic hit how did your guys
work change
well it was it was actually a
change that we were slowly making
anyways bringing our classes online and
this just kind of
pushed us to do it really quickly so
luckily we had been doing
some teaching online and some coaching
and some of our classes so we just
moved everything online really quickly
and it was amazing
because not only our current students
but lots of people were looking for
connection and kind of like what am i
going to do
i can't go to bars and parties and this
and that
so you know our mastery of relationship
class that was primarily in person
expanded like to three times the size
online within a couple of months
and it was like not that i wanted the
pandemic to happen
at all but it was actually there were
some positive things that came out of it
in terms of our teaching and being able
to reach
people all over the world you know
basically we embraced
change and when it happened we just said
yes
okay you know what's what's required
here
there was always a lot of innovation and
change in what we do by the very nature
of it and the organization
actually kind of had that that uh
theme as well so when the pandemic came
we were like okay
you know online great boom boom boom you
know in three weeks we were completely
set up we were just
you know like that and we found
it was really surprising because
you can touch people and be touched by
people and reach people
through zoom online in ways that i
wouldn't have thought
it's because the you know the spirit or
the being
yeah sort of in the body in a particular
way but it's also not really limited to
that
so if people are really present like we
just met you jacob but like i feel you
you feel us there's a lot of infinity
there's a closeness we're in each
other's space we're in each other's
experience
like we're actually very close in a
particular way if we're willing to
acknowledge it
since we're being open you're being very
open we're a little open
so you know it's it we just kind of
embraced change in a situation and
from alicia's history of having a
you know great parents i have great
in-laws she's got a kind of
natural ability to do that for me all
the difficulties i've had to undergo
i also have an ability to embrace change
and romantic relationship
really requires that and the pandemic
really requires that
right right yeah yeah so i i even
noticed just in this podcast because i i
started out um
doing in person i had i had a nice
little studio set up
um and then once covid came around had
to switch to zoom
and uh it took me a little bit you know
and but
i started kind of realizing what what
you just said is
you really can get a good connection on
here as it turns out
um you can really kind of just lock into
the conversation with with one another
it is a little bit different than um um
in person
but i i was i was pretty pretty happy
with how quickly i was able to adjust
and the guests are able to adjust and we
can be here with one another
um so what what are you guys seeing
coming up
since the pandemic um what's
what are the the people in your
audiences that the people you guys are
working with um what's coming up a lot
like what are some some common issues
um some things that some listeners may
be able to to go oh
that's that's happening with me i would
love to hear that that explained
yeah so the first thing i'll say is that
like any big you know crisis or big
event
it exacerbates things that are already
there
so for example a lot of people we work
with both
singles and couples and of course as
singles
especially with the pandemic but even
beforehand
online dating is a huge thing it's like
a big way to meet people
prior to the pandemic we would always
support people and like yeah
do some online dating have fun with the
apps here's how to do this effectively
but go to house parties meet people like
mingle
right because in person is great that
was impossible once the pandemic hit
so people that are single have felt
isolated and felt like oh my gosh
i really want to meet my person my
soulmate you know there's some people
that were
kind of of the age of wanting to have
kids and feeling like oh no
you know this is getting delayed so
we've been working
with our singles on how to successfully
online date
and how to safely
move the relationship forward you know
from initially hooking up with someone
on an app and then
um getting on zoom and meeting each
other and then
being in person eventually like that's
okay if you do it safely
a lot of people have been scared to do
that obviously because of covid so
and we've also discovered lots of um
like speed dating events online
that's actually the thing that works the
best is these
speed dating events online versus the
apps so we've discovered a bunch of
those
and helped our students navigate those
and that's a good tip
for your audience jacob speed dating
it's you know speed dating online is
pretty optimal because it's so
convenient
if i were single i would do two or three
speed dating events per
week literally oh wow you know they're
like 30 bucks
you know spend 30 to 90 bucks per week
meet five to 10 people every time you
get a lot of social interaction which
takes away from the loneliness and the
isolation
you potentially meet somebody we also as
alicia said support people on taking it
offline
but speed dating online is really
convenient it's it's pretty optimal
and it's generally a lot better than the
apps the apps
you know they can be good for hooking up
they can be good for getting into a
relationship
but they're way more difficult than
people think
right right so how does the online speed
dating work it's just
so you it's just kind of like this and
then it shifts through you meet
different people based off of interest
or
because i'm i'm uh i had been in a
relationship for 10 years
and we we split ways healthily we're
still
still friends um the like six seven
months ago
and i just totally haven't i haven't
done any of the dating apps i haven't
done any of the
any speed dating so um i i don't know i
just don't know a ton about it i guess
so
uh yeah so the way
that it works is that there's somebody
facilitating it and then they're just
rotating people into different breakout
rooms with each other for limited
amounts of time
so you can connect with someone briefly
and then you can show interest in the
people that you
are interested in later and they have a
system for that and then they match you
and they're usually uh have a theme
right like some speed dating is about
you know
uh whatever you know being jewish or
being christian or being new age or
being interested in
uh you know uh i don't know films or
whatever
and the other way they sort of segment
it is by age group
so you kind of you know you go to one
that has an age group you like maybe one
that has a theme you like
and then you meet people who are in that
and you get a lot more information about
them because you're really
interacting right right cool oh
that's awesome i hope that i hope just
that little description encourages
people to go to go give it a try
i've uh i've been trying to flirt with
the idea in my head more and try to you
know think about
expanding and moving on to the next
stage of life and uh you know
allowing myself to meet people so
working on that myself of course
um so i i i was kind of curious
could you guys explain how does how does
um a lens of psychology
really fit in with um um being in tune
with our sexual selves like how does
so how do someone who doesn't study
psychology or know much about it
they might be like well how does how
does psychology and you know learning
about your mind and your emotions and
these sort of things what does that have
to do with sex
yeah so we have a term for psychology we
call it a person's relationship
blueprint
and that relationship blueprint is
something that's forged
in the crucible of our childhood that
sounds very profound
but it's true we all know it's true
right like our you know
how how our parents related with us and
how we related with them and how they
related with each other
is basically how we learn to relate
and most people's relationship lives
whether it's colleagues or friends or
romantic relationships are
inside of that box
so we it's probably the most
difficult and the most important part of
our work there's really
sexy parts extended orgasm and flirting
and dating we've been talking a little
bit about that
that's really fun and great you know we
love supporting people in that stuff but
where the biggest difference is made is
usually
in a person seeing and understanding
their box
their relationship blueprint so they're
not limited by that box and not
reproducing the same relationship or
lack of relationship
over and over again
yeah yeah um yeah i noticed uh um
i i was watching a couple of the videos
i was trying to just pull it up here
um alicia you had talked about one that
kind of stood out um
you were working with someone who i
think it was basically
um around around when it take
sorry around when it came time to get
sensual around these moments
um she would kind of bring up some drama
she would she would kind of create
her own friction or you know it would
cause an argument
around these things i thought that was
that was super interesting you know
because i think
that that of course seems kind of
unconscious right you know who who would
want to do that
who would who would you know knowingly
try to bring arguments when
when they would like to release that
tension in in another way
um could you could you elaborate a
little bit on that alicia
yes yeah i know the example that you're
talking about and um
with this couple that i work with and
there's something like on one level
she was like yeah you know i want more
sexual activity in the relationship
i want to be more turned on they've been
together for years
and she didn't quite have her hands
around why they weren't
and so as we inquired into it we
realized oh
she actually starts to feel like a
little scared and like
uncomfortable and unsure of herself and
insecure when she gets closer to
intimacy and sexuality
and she was like not aware of that all
and she would unconsciously act out
you know pick a little fight or find
some reason to avoid and then later
complain
and it's these funny things we do as
human beings where we say we want one
thing and then that might actually be
our heart's desire but then if we're not
aware
of what's unconsciously driving us it
can actually sabotage
what we want yeah so how do we how do we
bring
awareness so if anybody's uh you know
saying oh that kind of sounds like me
i think we do that you know i want to
work on that how do we
that that first step i think is always
awareness right you know that's right
get a look at awareness is the most
important i'm sorry go ahead
no no no go ahead elaborate you're right
awareness is the most important part
there's four practices
that we have our students do ideally
daily i don't know if they all do them
daily but we
recommend they do them daily the first
one is meditate that's really just
cultivating awareness it's like having a
garden of awareness
in your space that you're cultivating we
think that's the most important that's
what i picked up at the zen monastery
and the yoga ashram second one is
psychological
inquiry what's going on with me right
now ooh you know i'm kind of
turned on but like you know i'm sort of
in the opposite house
uh opposite side of the house from
alicia and like i'm kind of avoiding her
or something like that like okay what is
that about ooh
you know i'm kind of scared you know to
sort out what's going on in the moment
for us bring the unconscious conscious
so that's
psychology or person's relationship
blueprint we recommend some
psychological inquiry every day
doesn't need to be a big therapy session
it can be two minutes of journal writing
or just
sitting down in an easy chair saying hey
what's what's going on with me right now
you know
like that third thing is body practice
especially in the pandemic particularly
important
people are really in their heads as
human beings our brain is most developed
of all of our
organs and systems compared to other
animals so people just end up in their
heads and when we're spending a lot of
time
without social interaction in our houses
on zoom etc
really easy to do that right so body
practice could be anything right now
i've got this mat
under my feet you can't see it but like
i'm rolling around this
sort of ball with my feet and that kind
of thing and i've got a yoga block there
and there's some texture
and like you know we've got sort of yoga
props kind of all around our house
so we're sort of like always doing yoga
it could be walking
body practice could be walking around
barefoot it could be lifting weights
it could be taking a shower it could be
anything but just there's a consistent
practice to stay in one's body
and then the fourth one is sensual
practice which can be
anything of the senses from music to
incense
all the way to sexual practice practiced
alone
or with a partner we have a whole set of
practices
so daily practice
is what makes a difference that's
another thing i picked up in the zen
monastery
people kind of think that intellectually
knowing something
is really living it or or knowing it or
but that's not true
so the most famous zen master said
practice
is enlightenment that just totally blew
me away
so those are the ones that we've found
make the biggest difference
yeah yeah i i was thinking about uh i i
forget who says it but before
enlightenment
uh chop wood carry water after
enlightenment chop would carry water
yeah i love mentioning that practice you
know in a i think that is something very
important especially with us
you know we're more on our computers a
lot of us have switched our jobs to zoom
in these sort of things i think uh you
know the act of movement you're saying
you're moving your feet around you know
i have a
one of those massage guns i like to use
that every morning and i think that
probably does help you know um
is that kind of related would you say
you know as we feel
more present confident and
you know connected to to our bodies that
helps us be more open and willing to
you know meet that within our partner
would you say
definitely we often say
that you could put any two people
together
that are you know whoever they're
attracted to a man with a woman
or it could be woman woman man man and
if you're
open in your body and your heart
and your mind like you will be turned on
towards each other and you will get
along
the mind closure and all those patterns
is what gets in the way you know couples
will often come to us
like we have decreased chemistry and
what do we do and should we still be
together
and we're like there's nothing wrong
with your bodies your bodies work
perfectly
so moving through those patterns and
opening the body and being in the body
can lead to a lot of connection
in chemistry right um did you guys
i mean you you mentioned awakenings for
you did you have awakenings of
uh i i asked this because
did you have awakenings of kind of
realizing that you were disconnected
from your body before
at all um i feel like when i first kind
of discovered
uh meditation yoga a few years ago i'd
always been athletic and worked out
but i i had no idea i didn't realize i
was kind of like disconnected from my
body a lot of my
my workouts were more ego lifting you
know looking looking in the mirror and
um it's it's so hard to put my finger on
and try to describe with words but i
felt uh when i discovered yoga started
doing meditation i really started
understanding being in your body being
connected you know feeling
feeling your shirt touch your skin
instead of being lost in the mind and
feeling
you know temperature throughout your
body and in different pressure points
and
um the the i think the the first
opening of discovering
the the awareness of kind of keeping
your your mind
you're we're constantly thinking all the
time right
and i i believe that a lot of us don't
know that we're thinking we don't notice
that we're thinking a lot of us haven't
discovered that awareness
um and it's still kind of new to me just
a couple years but it did help me
come back into my body a lot so is is
there anything we could touch on
right here um to speak to people who
might
feel some sort of disconnect from their
body maybe they haven't explored too
much
too much yoga they haven't really dove
into meditation they haven't really
looked into
their thought process and how it affects
our physical bodies here because
i think if if we can all connect to our
bodies a little bit more of course
that's going to help in our romantic
relationships
yeah yeah i mean everything you said is
absolutely right
uh people are disconnected from their
bodies
and people are disconnected from their
experience
in a thought zone the matrix is a
perfect metaphor for that you know that
movie is
in some alternate reality we can imagine
stuff and people mostly
are living in kind of an imaginary
universe given by the relationship
blueprint and their thought process and
their work and all the rest of that kind
of stuff
almost all spiritual traditions use the
body
as a portal as a gateway to presence
because the body is actually happening i
could imagine pink elephants but there
there are actually no pink elephants
here you know
but my body is here your body's there
you know or
alicia's body is here you know that's
something that's actually happening
so concentration in the body serves as a
ballast
or an anchor to
the presence and to presence and then
from there
we can get into more subtle dimensions
of being or being a human being you know
emotions and feelings and things that
are actually real they're as there as
the body
you know love for example
right love really is there i mean if we
really feel into reality
deeply love everything is love that can
everything is made of love it's very
interesting
right from my childhood i never would
have expected that it was a big one
it was like oh wow you know you know now
in the background we all kind of know
that but we do so much imagining usually
of negative stuff and
you know all kinds of stuff because of
what we see on tv and lifestyle and our
histories and all the rest of that kind
of stuff
but focus in the body
trains one to concentrate and not be
distracted by the mind and concentration
is in short order
these days nowadays more than ever
because of the speed
of technology so body practice is more
required and
now than really it's ever been and it's
a portal
to awakening to being to love
and within oneself and in a partnership
you know romantic love and chemistry and
turn on and union
and intimacy yeah
yeah wow yeah i like that that's a great
explanation there um
as you were talking about us being kind
of more disconnected from our bodies
i was thinking about technology um and
how it's changed
there's a lot of wonderful benefits
right you know we have online dating we
have
the um dating apps we could have this
conversation that's so great um
but the what do you guys have any um
opinions or recommendations or um
experience with people uh around online
porn
is is that something that's that that we
can do healthily is that something that
maybe is better off you know for
relationships to stay away from do you
have any recommendations there
it's the overuse that is the problem
it's not porn that's the problem right i
mean a little porn is fine if you enjoy
that and of course there's some that's
you know more tasteful or not you know
whatever
more well done or more whatever than
others but
everybody has their own preferences and
things they like to explore so it's
really not
the porn right it's the overuse the
misuse and like
replacing real intimacy with that more
erotic
staring at a screen and that's difficult
you know because you know human beings
are not
wired up to have uh
you know potential sexual
visuals in our pocket on our phone any
time of day
you know for guys in particular that's
hard you know like i remember when i was
i don't know how old i was 14 or
something like that and like
you know it was like you know when i
first saw my first magazine that had
naked women and that kind of stuff like
it was weeks of like
walking by the newsstand you know being
too nervous to do anything and then like
finally buying it and like the guy
wrapping it in a newspaper
you know you know you know what to say
so it's like a big deal and a whole
process and that like
and it was a few relatively tasteful
pictures it was like playboy or
something right you know you know what
i'm saying
you know not necessarily realistic
pictures but
you know because nobody really looks
like that exactly but you know what i
mean it was a
you know it now it's very hard on males
in particular but both sexes that
there's this
massive funnel of any kind of sex you
want to see like
available right in your pocket and
most of it is very low quality very goal
oriented
so it's you know it's a little bit like
being an alcoholic
and living in a bar right
yeah yeah i i think that it's uh it's
interesting thinking about how
for you when you first dove into porn
like how different it would be for
you know young people now where again
it's it's it's all right well i'm going
to check this thing out and then you
just
click a couple times and you have
thousands and millions of
just the most insane you know uh just i
i i think i imagine as a young person
you know diving into the world of online
pornography
it'd be just mind-blowing to see all of
these things before you really know any
like knowledge
or um real you know how it may be
in real life in in um what you can
expect going forward i think
we probably do put we bring in different
expectations
into our relationships um without the
knowledge
uh of things being different than they
than they appear on the screen so um
how do we
let's see how do we bring in oh
oh sorry here's where i want to go a
diet i did want to mention
apologize i'm a little all over the
place today changing diet
you did mention that diet was something
important when it comes to intimacy is
this something that could help
you know relationships who have been
together for a while
maybe they're they're kind of like
losing some of their spark because
they're eating bad food
during times that they could be kind of
keeping a little bit lighter is is that
where diet comes in
diets really important and everything
that you're saying sort of point there's
a word that comes to mind with all the
sort of different areas that you brought
up jacob and that's lifestyle
right you know like how we're living i
would say the biggest challenge people
have to great romantic relationships is
their relationship blueprint their sort
of
internal pattern but then there is the
external pattern
how much they're working what they're
eating pornography
technology so the the way we work with
people with those
issues is or those sort of external
environmental issues
is setting up a life
that actually works for the person and
for their remote
romantic life and relationship life
because most people's lives are not
really actually set up
to have a great relationship you know if
you're a couple
and expect you know we have a boy a
beautiful boy
you know but we work with each other and
like we work in our house and all the
rest of this kind of stuff so we have as
much time together as we want
if you're two people working two 50-hour
week jobs
and you have a child you know much less
than a pandemic like where is the time
for the relationship right you know and
then if
if there's like you know eating things
that are kind of draining
you know that kind of thing like okay
then there's less vitality
you know if there's you know a lot of
watching porn then that's usually kind
of hidden in secret and private and that
brings
division and a lack of turn on
especially because
for men in particular who most porn is
watched by men
you know it's it's very goal oriented or
ejaculation focused
so if a guy's watching a lot of porn and
ejaculating a lot
he's going to be really drained there's
not going to be much response left
for real women in his life or if he's in
a relationship a real woman in his life
so all of these are really big issues
and that's the second category of
challenges
that we work with people on the
environment and the external
diets important um
you know and if i were to i mean you
know that's not our like super duper
specialty but
uh yeah eating healthy is really
important
yeah there's a couple that i'm working
with and they they're a young couple
they have two little kids you know they
both
work these crazy tech jobs and they're
just like ah
and one of the things they said in one
of the first couple sessions i had with
them they're like
we're couch potatoes you know after the
whole day
and the the work and the kids and then
they're in bed and like we just wanna
on the couch and eat potato chips and
watch netflix
there's nothing wrong with that
inherently but there wasn't
time set aside for their relationship
you know i mean it's one thing
and it's a beautiful thing to have goals
in your relationship life a vision like
yeah let's connect more let's have more
sex let's
be more intimate but it's so important
to actually
get that into your schedule and your
calendar i mean we're
huge fans of actually scheduling you
know for
people that are in relationship we call
it pleasure time
it is literally in our calendar every
morning at 9 15
is our pleasure time you know we have
sex and practice extended orgasm and
talk and hang out
and then we have other times a few times
a week to do this
relationship inquiry together you have
to like put it in there it's not just
going to happen
right yeah yeah that's wonderful i i
really like that uh
planning it putting it on the calendar
what is there any other bits of pieces
of advice that you can offer
um people in relationships during the
pandemic i have plenty of friends
um who who i i'm sure could could could
use some advice around these
these realms you know who uh suddenly
all all the fun
because because i think of all the uh
the date nights that we're not no longer
able to do
or you know maybe the date nights are
just different they're kind of at home
um things are starting to slowly open
back up there's some outdoor seating and
stuff
at certain bars and whatnot but uh yeah
so so
what what are some other uh uh helpful
tips and tricks for people in
relationships to kind of
keep the spark going amidst the pandemic
here all right i'll say two or three
things if you want to add any
um to write on the coattails of what
alicia was saying
in it take an hour a day and
have it be pleasure time it doesn't
necessarily need to be sexual but if
you're in a relationship
half an hour a day that you're spending
with each other doing
something fun and if that
time can't be found then declare a
breakdown
you know if if if we can't find an hour
a day for the relationship it's a really
good idea to say hey wow there's a
problem
you know there's something that's not
working and that's often difficult for
people to
just simply acknowledge neutrally
without
making it bad but just telling the truth
like okay you know we can't find an hour
a day that's a problem thing you know
like that
so find an hour a day for uh having fun
for maybe romantic connection maybe
going for a walk
you know that kind of thing second thing
is
even in the pandemic because we have a
child
right so you know all of a sudden like
you know we we couldn't take him to
playgrounds
you know so it was a you know really big
change so i bought
a tourist book for san francisco
and it turned out to be a gold mine
it was amazing it's like i discovered
san francisco
so even though we're in a pandemic
there's tons of places to go and we
started going out
more and yeah we can't do the usual
things
but it's kind of like where we started
our conversation jacob
if we embrace change there's usually all
kinds of opportunities
so it turned into you know going all i
mean san francisco has like
six beaches and you know all kinds of
natural things that i didn't know about
and now we're
going to all those kind of places and
picnics and all kinds of stuff
so it does take adapting so the first
thing is set up some time for the
relationship the second thing is
be willing to adapt and find
the things that you can do and you might
be really surprised
because you know there might actually be
even better things to do
than before you know for example i watch
more netflix now than i used to but one
thing i found is that like i really like
documentaries there's like a gazillion
great documentaries so instead of
watching all this like
stuff that's crushing my spirit i'm
watching things they're like i'm
learning and it's interesting and
i'm reading more and reading i like
biographies and
you know so it's kind of like that yes
and and related to what you were just
saying erwin
um to wake up to the fact that like wow
we're in a relationship and we're having
trouble making time for each other
every day it's like unless it was an
arranged
marriage or an arranged relationship
which does happen but not a lot you know
in this country
you got together with the person because
you have the hots for them you know like
it was
it was hot it was sexy at some point and
that's why you're with the person that's
the main reason it's not you know
there's other good things we do with our
partners like we have
families some of us or we get into a
house and we live together we build a
life together
but to ignore or de-prioritize that main
reason you're together is like
you know it's never urgent unless it
gets urgent
you know you just want to nurture it
so too practical to make everything we
said a little bit
you know practical if i love what alicia
just said if
if a couple said okay we're going to use
this pandemic as an opportunity to learn
extended orgasm
right and then they took that that sort
of condensed space that they're in
and then they use that and focus that
you know in the long run the pandemic
would have been a blessing
right or for a couple or people who are
single if they use
okay we're in all this sort of private
space together we're going to use it
as a spiritual retreat or a meditation
retreat
right in the long run it would be a
blessing
so you know it anything to you know i've
heard
lectures by people who are in solitary
confinement
and used it as an opportunity to
meditate
the most obvious example is not exactly
solitary confinement but as nelson
mandela
nelson mandela came out of 20 years of
prison
tortured most of those days a better
human being than he went in
yeah incredible yeah yeah i i love that
it really is all about your your framing
you know your mindset that you're
bringing into it you know i i think a
lot of us
uh could benefit from kind of shifting
our all right how can we turn this into
a positive how can we uh you know add
some spice into our love life and
and uh not not kind of take this beating
from
the lock down so to say um i do want to
uh
explore a bit more on the extended
orgasm so
that was new information to me i i
honestly can't say that i had i had ever
heard about that
um i i thought it was the typical you
know
six to 12 seconds situation i didn't
realize uh
there was a opportunity for you know
this extended
sensual experience in our uh human
sexuality so
could we explore the difference i'm sure
you guys have already explained this a
few times in other videos which people
can check out on your youtube
um can you explore the difference or
explain the difference between
extended orgasm and regular yes so
what most people know as orgasm
is like a climax orgasm right we call it
traditional peak orgasm you know you're
going along you know let's say you're
with someone you're making out you're
getting more turned on
and it kind of plateaus a little bit
then then it spikes up and you go
over the edge and have that rapid set of
contractions and that
extreme pleasure you had an orgasm
that's awesome now extended orgasm
is having all of those same
signs of orgasm clinical signs
like involuntary contractions in the
genitals and
you know the extreme pleasure in the
genitals which is not really clinical
you can't really measure that but that
pleasure
and increased heart rate and all these
signs
over an extended period of time
your body has the ability to release
into a state of orgasm over time
versus having one little boop and it's
over
and how that's possible is by being
relaxed
because usually when people have a very
high level of sensitivity especially in
their genitals
they're very tense right so they tense
tense tense
you know the the genitals are gripped
and then they just
let go and relax or they get fatigued
and the genitals relax
and then they crash over the edge very
rapidly
but if you get to that high level of
sensitivity that's what we call the
orgasm line it's actually masters and
johnson's
the clinical sexologist from the last
century
they they distinguish the orgasm line
above this level of sensitivity in the
genitals a person will have an orgasm
so what we added to that is if you get
to that level of sensitivity
and you're relaxed you'll stay
above that line and you'll have all
those signs of orgasm that alicia was
talking about involuntary contractions
in the genitals
engorgement release etc for
really as long as you want to so what
you need
is high sensitivity in the genitals
above the orgasm line
and relaxation so
excuse me it's a little bit like if you
were filling a bathtub
instead of sort of filling the bathtub
with water
and then the water level rises you know
then you're above
a certain line of sensitivity let's say
you know water line
and then you open the drain you turn the
faucet off you open a drain the water
level goes down
instead you have the water rising and
the drain open the drain open is the
orgasm the release
and you have the sensitivity increasing
through all the body practice and
meditation and central practice
you're really good at adding chemistry
internal on a mile a minute but you're
not tensing up around it
so then the body stay you get past a
certain very very high level
and the body just stays at that level
it's funny because tomorrow
we have uh an extended orgasm course
online
yes we have courses about it because
you know most people can they're like oh
i can kind of get that
you sort of feel like yeah my body's
capable of that much pleasure
but people aren't quite sure how to get
there you know women especially we work
with a lot of women who come to us
and they're like you know i've never
really had an orgasm or i'm i'm not sure
if i've had one or um i can have them
by myself but it's hard with a partner
or like i have orgasms i want more
and you know from wherever you are
you can learn how to have extended
orgasm
right yeah so so why is this why is this
such
new information the extended orgasm you
know you think we have so many years of
exploring our bodies and learning about
our bodies and minds and how our
psychology works with our bodies
why does it seem like this like um
you know padlocked thing or something
you know because
it seems like a a beautiful wonderful
thing that
that you know a lot more people should
should be able to explore and experience
in their life is is it just kind of like
the the western model
of of society life uh wha
why is this so you know i guess
you know what why is it it's strange to
me that i'm just now learning about this
you know you think that
there would be information floating
around about this something you would
think right
but but people are very sexually
repressed i mean on average people in
the east
are more sexually repressed than they
are in the west i mean sexual repression
really is the norm
and you can look at it from a
psychological viewpoint conditioning in
childhood and life and culture and all
the rest of that
but it's probably better to take a sort
of longer view
you know maybe a historical or
evolutionary view
you know sex is a big deal you know
throughout most of human history
even prehistory uh you know
getting pregnant is a super big deal it
changes life
completely um you know it's potentially
dangerous diseases all kinds of stuff so
it's
you know the pill condoms this kind of
thing
these are this little tiny little blip
you know in
in human evolution like this little tiny
fraction
in like miles and miles of you know
history and time and like that so you
know there's a lot of
uh holding and gripping around sex you
know even
mammals if you look at mammals like you
know
their sex is kind of like they get kind
of agitated about it and it's kind of a
big deal and like that
so you know we're just catching up
with uh what's possible sexually
and relaxing during sex you know as a
species we're just kind of
opening up to it um
and you know the cultures and the norms
or are
you know just starting to kind of
release and unfold
and all of that tension and fear is held
in people's bodies
you know people are you know kind of
constrained and tight and and afraid
and you know uh it's uh
you know it's a really big deal to open
up sexually with somebody
you know there's a lot you know you
really especially for extended orgasm
you have to open your heart
and your mind and your body and like
you know it's it's kind of like you know
taking
uh acid it's going to be a really good
trip or it's going to be really
difficult you know and once you get the
hang of it that's why we
work very gradually with people we
usually have people start
with just you know with their partner or
if they're single
with themselves but let's say with a
partner you know one person will just
put their hand on the partner's heart
and partner's abdomen
we call it deep touch you know maybe do
a few weeks of just deep touch
or in the pleasure course even couples
will have them practice individually
masturbating kind of learning about this
kind of thing
so that the entry is very very gradual
so that their psychology and their mind
can
keep up with the intensity and so they
don't
basically blow out or go unconscious
yeah wow yeah that's cool i mean i i
love that you guys are teaching about
this because i feel like it's a
you know it's it's a corner of of
conversation that
um you know i think our our culture does
have uh you know a
bit of shame and repression around
around uh
sexual you know uh sex intimacy
uh you know a lot of our romantic side
so i think that it's great that you guys
are doing this when you were talking
about
um erwin when you're talking about you
know the the release like the
the tightening that we have uh
interiorly
the tightening that we have of our
muscles and the tension that we hold
uh that was when i first started doing
yoga and meditation
uh just just a few years ago i
that was something that i learned i was
like oh i didn't realize it but i was
i'm holding tension in areas that i
never knew and you know you do guided
meditations though
you'll be sitting there for a few
minutes following your breath and
they'll
inquire you to you know let go let go of
the holding you're doing around your
eyes
let go of the holding you're doing
around your arms that sort of thing
so um i i i imagine that when it comes
to
the extended orgasm it's probably a lot
of that like
you're kind of letting go of things that
you didn't realize you were holding
internally does that sound all right yes
especially your mind
especially remind you yeah and and to
and to do
to let go in a somatic way
the work we do with people is very
somatic uh you know
for example we might have people breathe
into their pelvis
you know breathe into their pelvis feel
it
you know notice that tension they're
probably holding
gradually release it actually practice
some exercises like
a kegel pulling the genitals in but or a
moulabanda like a yogic lock
in the pelvis but then also pushing out
you can read all those
old texts the taoist texts and the yogic
texts
none of them actually even talk about
pushing out right they all talk about
the mulabanda kind of pulling in but
pushing out is actually more important
because there's already so much tension
there so have people practice those kind
of exercises
breathe the energy up the spine down the
front
that's a classic taoist exercise
breathing up spine down the front or
kundalini exercise
up the spine right and in our
addition is we really bring it into
everyday life
and relationship and orgasm and
emphasize the pushing out and how do you
keep the
genitals in that kind of nice relaxed
juicy place
it accentuates spiritual life and
chemistry and romantic life and
you know it just it just kind of makes
us happier because there's not a
missing link in the chain
of our body and mind when there's a
missing link in that chain
you know there's a there's less zing
jing enthusiasm
vibrancy energy you know fun turn on
let you know it's it's just less of a
good time so
you know sometimes i don't say it this
way anymore
but you know i used to say you know can
people take it the wrong way but you
know we're kind of a
school about learning how to party you
know
but like you know people now a days
think that that means you know taking a
bunch of drugs that's not really our
thing
yeah yeah no i i resonate with that i
like that i like uh
i i like that phrasing i think that
still works um
well so so we are getting up here in
time you two i really appreciate your
time i really appreciate you coming on
here and uh
and allowing me to poke and prod and ask
ask the questions
so you guys have have some workshops who
you can find we can find you on youtube
you do have an online online website
what where else can we find out where
else if we want if anybody wants to dive
more into this
where do they go yes so the best way to
do that
actually if you're listening to this and
you're like wow cool
you know i want to know what extended
orgasm is or oh i want to get into that
relationship or whatever if something
just really touched you
i'm offering love life consultations and
you can set one up with me by texting
erwan dave on teachings
i'll give you the phone number it's
415-308-9580
it's 415-308-9580
and you just tell me your name and that
you heard about us here
on the podcast and that you want to set
up a consultation and then we'll
schedule it from there and in the
consultation you can tell me
whatever you want to tell me about your
your goals your challenges your desires
and your love life and your sex life and
we'll look and see which of our programs
would be the best fit
we have private coaching and we have
classes like weekly year-long classes
and weekend intensives and all sorts of
fun stuff
wonderful beautiful uh okay well let
let's do one one last question and then
we'll end it here
uh for for each of you could answer
individually um
what does the world need more of right
now
um you know consciousness
love it awareness yes yeah i was going
to say
uh well besides when i said love sweet
love in my head with the song
uh like relaxation and enjoyment
perfect perfect answers uh i really
appreciate it you too i appreciate your
time i appreciate you guys doing
doing this work you know like i said to
me anyway there's not a ton of people
that i know of that are doing these
things and
i think we should we should be invited
more to
explore our own uh physiology psychology
how it all relates
uh you know the the wonderful
experiences we're all able to have as
humans on this planet so
uh thanks again so much you guys uh i i
will be in touch via email listeners
take care of yourselves
drink some water check out these two uh
send some send some text to alicia if
you are interested in
exploring more thanks again
take care guys
[Music]
foreign
knowledge is power
you